Andrew Kang

ENGINEERING MANAGER

Personal Profile

A seasoned professional with proven history of developing and maintaining sophisticated multi-component real-time system and excellent problem-solving skills. 8+ years of experience in financial and payment industry.

Areas of Expertise

- Java Microservices
- Spring Boot
- Angular
- Large-scale Statistical Analysis
- Pattern Recognition
- Data Mining
- Data ETL
- Oracle SQL
- Pivotal Gemfire Data Grid
- Shell Scripts

Education History

UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI ST LOUIS
BA MATHEMATICS | CUM LAUDE
Minors: Computer Science, Statistics

Get in Contact

- Mobile: 314-662-2198
- andykang151@gmail.com
- 389 Washington St, Apt 28G, Jersey City NJ 07302

Work Experience

VICE PRESIDENT / SENIOR SPECIALIST - FULL STACK

BANK OF NEW YORK MELLON | AUG 2021 - PRESENT

- Designed, analyzed, coordinated the repo transaction settlement and voucher management automation system with Spring boot, Angular and Hazelnut.
- Implemented a modular, extendable, and 100% automated system for managing BNY Mellon trade settlement.
- Set up customer-facing, data-focused interactive interface that help users search for trade positions.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MASTERCARD | OCT 2017 - AUG 2021

- Developed full-stack projects using Spring-boot and Java Microservice design pattern for backend and Angular for frontend
- Managed micro service projects deployed on Pivotal Cloud Foundry
- Conducted comprehensive data analysis on fraudulent transactions and created data visualization reports for the senior management team

ENGINEER II

MASTERCARD | MAR 2015 - OCT 2017

- Improved simulation testing using Core Java on Mastercard Flexible Transaction Processor that manages tens of millions of transactions every day
- Assisted data scientists on feature collection and data discovery for building ML models to detect flash fraud attacks

ENGINEER I

MASTERCARD | AUG 2013 -MAR 2015

- Performed complicated statistical analysis using Oracle SQL on billions of MasterCard transactions
- Developed and authored IBM ILOG JRULE-based fraud detection rules for hundreds of MasterCard Cyber and Intelligence Fraud Rule Manager (FRM) customers

Patent

SYSTEMS AND METHODS FOR USE IN NETWORK SERVICES MIGRATION

ISSUED MAR 2021 US 16/114910

Multi-component data ETL system that drives customer migration by sophisticated data transformation between Oracle, GemFire Grid and IBM Operational Decision Management System